<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on GetLatestVersion – Europe</title><link>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/</link><description>Recent content in Home on GetLatestVersion – Europe</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 16:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.getlatestversion.eu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Code dependencies: Binary Composition is not only a mathematics calculation</title><link>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/2020/05/code-dependencies-binary-composition-is-not-only-a-mathematics-calculation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/2020/05/code-dependencies-binary-composition-is-not-only-a-mathematics-calculation/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Over the years, the growing code base of application software with multiple teams working on the same product, has lead to break up the solution into multiple solutions. This has been done trying to reduce the time required for the build and for their integration, to ease Integrated Development Environment in opening hundreds of projects, and other.
The main consequence of having multiple solutions is binary composition.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="what-is-binary-composition">What is binary composition?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Binary composition occurs when one or more solutions reference the compiled binaries of another solution. Let suppose it is needed to make the binaries of Solution B available to Solution A before Solution A can build successfully.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="visual-studio-references.jpg" alt="image.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are forced to commit the code together with the binaries produced by build in the repository&amp;hellip;Keep on reading :)&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="how-can-we-distribute-binaries">How can we distribute binaries?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>We can make those binaries available in several ways.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="git-repository">Git repository&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A first possibility consists in committing them into a repository anytime a merge into the development/master branch by means of the Continuous Integration build pipeline is requested by a Pull Request. Of course, this increases the size of the repository introducing significant slowdown checkout times and performances. Imagine what could happen if teams work on different branches ending up using different versions of the same binaries creating merge conflicts.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="file-share">File share&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Another option consists in putting the binaries onto a file share. In this case, however, there is no index to find binaries quickly and there is no protection against overriding a version.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="package-management-with-azure-artifacts">Package Management with Azure Artifacts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This should definitely be the most suitable solution because it allows putting binaries into NuGet (and other as npm, Maven, Python, and universal) packages making it possible for Solution A to reference these packages. Among the several advantages introduced by this methodology, in Continuous Integration Azure pipeline a NuGet published task can be added in order to make the update versioning procedure automatic and distributing it in a reliable way also.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About</title><link>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.getlatestversion.eu/images/320px-Flag_of_Europe.svg.png" alt="Europe flag">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="about-us">About Us&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>GetLatestVersion.eu stems from GetLatestVersion.it, the successful Italian community specialised on DevOps, Application Lifecycle Management (ALM) and Software Development Life-Cycle (SDLC).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-we-do">What we do&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We publish posts and articles on DevOps, Agile, tools, design, implementation techniques.
Our &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/GetLatestVersion">YouTube channel&lt;/a> hosts useful video of different kind: short introductions to a topic or tool, longer presentation on experiences and conference sessions.
In addition, we organise events in person and online on DevOps, Agile, ALM and SDLC topics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Privacy</title><link>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/page/privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/page/privacy/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="list-of-cookies-used-in-this-site">List of Cookies used in this site&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Google Analytics cookies&lt;/strong>: __utma, __utmb, __utmc, __utmv, __utmz, used to gather site statistic usage. You can read more info on Google Policies on: How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps and Safeguarding your Data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Search</title><link>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/search/</guid><description>&lt;p class="error message js-hidden">You must have Javascript enabled to use this function.&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="search-loading status message hidden">Loading search index…&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="search-input hidden">
&lt;form id="search-form" class="search-form" action="#" method="post" accept-charset="UTF-8" role="search">
&lt;label for="query" class="visually-hidden">Search&lt;/label>
&lt;input type="search" id="query" name="query" class="search-text" placeholder="Enter the terms you wish to search for." maxlength="128">
&lt;button type="submit" name="submit" class="form-submit" >Search&lt;/button>
&lt;/form>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="search-results">&lt;/div>
&lt;template>
&lt;article class="search-result list-view">
&lt;header>
&lt;h2 class="title title-submitted">&lt;a href="#">Title here&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="submitted">&lt;time class="created-date">Date here&lt;/time>&lt;/div>
&lt;/header>
&lt;div class="content">Summary here&lt;/div>
&lt;/article>
&lt;/template></description></item></channel></rss>