<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on GetLatestVersion – Europe</title><link>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/</link><description>Recent content in Home on GetLatestVersion – Europe</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 14:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.getlatestversion.eu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Top 10 Pipeline mistakes</title><link>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/2020/05/top-10-pipeline-mistakes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate><author>Giulio Vian</author><guid>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/2020/05/top-10-pipeline-mistakes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I am going to start a series of posts detailing common issues or mistakes in a DevOps context.
I will try to refer to my experience and add some practical suggestion to identify and solve these issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with my list of top 10 CI/CD pipeline issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-list">The list&lt;/h2>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>NOTE&lt;/strong>:&lt;br>
Published posts are in &lt;strong>bold&lt;/strong>, the link for items in &lt;em>italic&lt;/em> does not work.&lt;br>
Last update: 10 June 2020&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../sloppy-secrets-handling">&lt;em>Sloppy handling of Secrets&lt;/em>&lt;/a> &amp;ndash; leaking or hard-coding passwords, tokens or similar sensitive data;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../untraceable-artifacts">&lt;em>Untraceable artifacts&lt;/em>&lt;/a> &amp;ndash; when builds produce (or worse: deploy!) binaries of unknown source and version; this is a major red flag because it is cheap and easy to fix, but it is usually overlooked causing a major technical debt pile-up;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../too-specific">&lt;em>Too specific&lt;/em>&lt;/a> &amp;ndash; if your artifacts are not scrubbed from environment-specific dependencies, so they cannot be deployed to all environments;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../what-quality">&lt;em>What, quality?&lt;/em>&lt;/a> &amp;ndash; when your pipeline does not contain any check on quality, what do you expect as a result?;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../bleeding-edge">&lt;em>Bleeding edge&lt;/em>&lt;/a> &amp;ndash; using the latest and greatest technology is not always a wise choice;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../galactic-builds">&lt;em>Galactic Builds&lt;/em>&lt;/a> &amp;ndash; far-reaching builds that slow teams down instead of helping them;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../flaky-builds">&lt;strong>Flaky builds&lt;/strong>&lt;/a> &amp;ndash; builds generating unreproducible behaviours or random artefacts;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../too-much-of-a-good-thing">&lt;em>Too much of a good thing&lt;/em>&lt;/a> &amp;ndash; when you go too far to avoid the above mistakes, causing the fix to backfire;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../implicit-assumption">&lt;em>Implicit assumption&lt;/em>&lt;/a> &amp;ndash; any build that breaks when some undocumented environmental condition change;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="../untamed-plugins">&lt;em>Untamed plugins&lt;/em>&lt;/a> &amp;ndash; similar to the previous one, it is the nightmare of people that manage your build environments, when the build software uses too many, or even conflicting plugins.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The list is not really complete: there is one more to add.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-unforgivable-sin-having-no-pipeline">The unforgivable sin: having no pipeline&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is the ultimate sin of any developer: having no automated process of any kind.&lt;br>
At a minimum you can have a simple bash or PowerShell script to compile and publish your project.
With that it is going to be easy to integrate it in any of the most popular Continuous Integration tools: Jenkins, Azure DevOps, GitHub Actions, GitLab, TeamCity, etc.&lt;br>
That script should check for dependencies and label the produced artifacts with a version number. This will be discussed in detail in future posts.&lt;br>
If you do not need to automate the process for other people, at least, automate it for your future self!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See you soon with the next episode.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Code dependencies: Binary Composition is not only a mathematics calculation</title><link>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/2020/05/code-dependencies-binary-composition-is-not-only-a-mathematics-calculation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Bartolomeo Lombardi</author><guid>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/2020/05/code-dependencies-binary-composition-is-not-only-a-mathematics-calculation/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Over the years, the growing code base of application software with multiple teams working on the same product, has lead to break up the solution into multiple solutions. This has been done trying to reduce the time required for the build and for their integration, to ease Integrated Development Environment in opening hundreds of projects, and other.
The main consequence of having multiple solutions is binary composition.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="what-is-binary-composition">What is binary composition?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Binary composition occurs when one or more solutions reference the compiled binaries of another solution. Let suppose it is needed to make the binaries of Solution B available to Solution A before Solution A can build successfully.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="visual-studio-references.jpg" alt="image.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are forced to commit the code together with the binaries produced by build in the repository&amp;hellip;Keep on reading :)&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="how-can-we-distribute-binaries">How can we distribute binaries?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>We can make those binaries available in several ways.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="git-repository">Git repository&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>A first possibility consists in committing them into a repository anytime a merge into the development/master branch by means of the Continuous Integration build pipeline is requested by a Pull Request. Of course, this increases the size of the repository introducing significant slowdown checkout times and performances. Imagine what could happen if teams work on different branches ending up using different versions of the same binaries creating merge conflicts.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="file-share">File share&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Another option consists in putting the binaries onto a file share. In this case, however, there is no index to find binaries quickly and there is no protection against overriding a version.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="package-management-with-azure-artifacts">Package Management with Azure Artifacts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This should definitely be the most suitable solution because it allows putting binaries into NuGet (and other as npm, Maven, Python, and universal) packages making it possible for Solution A to reference these packages. Among the several advantages introduced by this methodology, in Continuous Integration Azure pipeline a NuGet published task can be added in order to make the update versioning procedure automatic and distributing it in a reliable way also.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reducing the gap between operations and development using Azure DevOps</title><link>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/2020/05/reducing-the-gap-between-operations-and-development-using-azure-devops/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 11:30:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Alessandro Alpi</author><guid>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/2020/05/reducing-the-gap-between-operations-and-development-using-azure-devops/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>As we all know, DevOps is culture. In a company that is going to adopt its practices and principles, everyone should be &amp;ldquo;on the same side&amp;rdquo;. Continuous improvement cannot be part of our work in IT if we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t reduce the gap between development and operations. People like me, that worked in the 90s, know that dev and ops were always isolated in silos and this was &amp;ldquo;the only&amp;rdquo; way that everyone followed as a suggestion taken from the market leaders. Ticketing systems and extreme bureaucracy acted as a man-in-the-middle between those silos, transforming each organization in two people-unaware endpoints.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Speaking from a DevOps perspective, in such circumstances, a developer couldn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about how to deploy, where and how is an environment configured. On the other hand, an operation guy couldn&amp;rsquo;t get anything from a package in terms of what the application has been made for. Due to this gap we often see performance issues, underestimated hardware stuff and delayed releases. Last but not least, what about the lack of commitment and accountability of the employees working on the solution? In short, reducing such a gap is possible using a combination of DevOps culture and the right tools. We will see hereafter how my organization tries to do so using Azure DevOps.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="scenario">Scenario&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s get started with our team (DevTeam hereafter), which is working with agile methodologies, composed of ten developers and a PO. A quick note, we are using a process decision framework called &lt;a href="https://www.disciplinedagileconsortium.org">Disciplined Agile&lt;/a>. Then, we have three operation professionals (OpsTeam from now on). Build and deploy pipelines already exist. Builds are hosted by &lt;a href="https://azure.microsoft.com/it-it/services/devops/">Azure DevOps (cloud)&lt;/a> and deploys are managed by &lt;a href="https://octopus.com/">Octopus Deploy&lt;/a>. Getting this, has been a difficult mission.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everything is related to infrastructure in terms of servers, operative systems, virtual hosts, DNS, firewalls, security and so on, is the responsibility of our OpsTeam. As a result, they do many tasks for managing the environments. Here comes the problem. DevTeams used to create tasks in a dedicated backlog, but OpsTeam didn&amp;rsquo;t. It&amp;rsquo;s not just a matter of end-of-pipeline tasks, but also tasks for their daily basis work.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="our-solution">Our solution&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Modify the tool, adapting its shape in order to fit in with that real scenario. A piece of cake, when you&amp;rsquo;re DevOps &amp;ldquo;inside&amp;rdquo;. How did we change Azure DevOps? Let&amp;rsquo;s describe what we did in three parts:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="teams-in-azure-devops">Teams in Azure DevOps&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To create a team in Azure DevOps is really a piece of cake (according to the latest releases). Just navigate to the options and select &lt;em>Teams&lt;/em>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="post01-01-team-on-azuredevops.png" alt="image.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can add many teams clicking on &lt;em>New team&lt;/em>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="post01-02-new-team.png" alt="image.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can set the team&amp;rsquo;s administrators, the permission set and an area under which every work item will be created. This area will be one of our best friends, especially when we will make our queries for gathering and analyzing the team&amp;rsquo;s related data. Additionally, also the other teams&amp;rsquo; members could create items with this area in order to make the OpsTeam aware of them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Team&amp;rsquo;s backlog
Now let&amp;rsquo;s navigate to Backlogs:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="post01-03-backlogs.png" alt="image.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Good! The new backlog has been created. Going on it, we will see the team&amp;rsquo;s drop-down as well as the one for iterations. Great feature!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="post01-04-sprints.png" alt="image.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once created, we will see the teams&amp;rsquo; drop-down:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="post01-05-team-switch.png" alt="image.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="work-items">Work items&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Now, let&amp;rsquo;s create a new work item type. We call it Ops item. Navigate to Process customization page:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="post01-06-process.png" alt="image.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before adding the new work item, we must ensure that the process is already a custom process, otherwise, all the edits will be blocked as shown in the following picture:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="post01-07-process-custom.png" alt="image.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ve already created a SimplifiedScrum process. let&amp;rsquo;s add our item now:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="post01-07-workitemtype.png" alt="image.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now we are going to modify the fields of the new type. Each team should be able to understand all the item&amp;rsquo;s properties. We will leave the item as is in this example. Then, we have to map the type to the backlog item list, since only the default work item types are shown initially. To do this, navigate to the Process customization page, Backlog Levels tab:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="post01-08-process-add-workitemtype-1.png" alt="image.png">
&lt;img src="post01-09-process-add-workitemtype-2.png" alt="image.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As we can see, we can also set the default item for our requirements backlog. Moreover, every Sprint backlog, based on iterations, will enable us to add the new Ops item:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="post01-10-new-workitem.png" alt="image.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="wrapping-up">Wrapping up&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>So, we&amp;rsquo;ve got a backlog for the IT Operations team&amp;rsquo;s members. Then, we&amp;rsquo;ve related it to their Azure DevOps team. Additionally, we&amp;rsquo;ve got a particular work item type (not mandatory, but really useful for querying it or adding it into dashboards) target of IT Operations&amp;rsquo; job and a dedicated Area Path. We can make many relationships between items of both our backlogs. Here is an example of how an activity can be managed and organized (extension: &lt;a href="https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=ms-devlabs.WorkItemVisualization">Work Item Visualize&lt;/a>):&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="post01-11-workitem-visualize.png" alt="image.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you can see, the Ops items are &lt;em>Successor&lt;/em> of the &amp;ldquo;development&amp;rdquo; Product backlog items. Indeed, the Ops Items will be finished after the PBI, typically. Think about creating s DNS or a network path to let the production app work in production.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="conclusions">Conclusions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With this solution, we&amp;rsquo;re decoupling backlogs. Moreover, we&amp;rsquo;re isolating the management maintaining the relationships between work items that reside on different boards. At the same time, we&amp;rsquo;re making a strong synergy between Development and Operations.
Then, in a couple of clicks, we can switch teams and backlogs, using Azure DevOps Boards. We can track changes in both the departments, also for audit requirements. In my opinion, this helps the enterprise awareness and facilitates the continuous improvement of all the teams and any member&amp;rsquo;s skill.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About</title><link>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://www.getlatestversion.eu/images/320px-Flag_of_Europe.svg.png" alt="Europe flag">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="about-us">About Us&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>GetLatestVersion.eu stems from GetLatestVersion.it, the successful Italian community specialised on DevOps, Application Lifecycle Management (ALM) and Software Development Life-Cycle (SDLC).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-we-do">What we do&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We publish posts and articles on DevOps, Agile, tools, design, implementation techniques.
Our &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/GetLatestVersion">YouTube channel&lt;/a> hosts useful video of different kind: short introductions to a topic or tool, longer presentation on experiences and conference sessions.
In addition, we organise events in person and online on DevOps, Agile, ALM and SDLC topics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Privacy</title><link>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/page/privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/page/privacy/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="list-of-cookies-used-in-this-site">List of Cookies used in this site&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Google Analytics cookies&lt;/strong>: __utma, __utmb, __utmc, __utmv, __utmz, used to gather site statistic usage. You can read more info on Google Policies on: How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps and Safeguarding your Data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Search</title><link>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://www.getlatestversion.eu/search/</guid><description>&lt;p class="error message js-hidden">You must have Javascript enabled to use this function.&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="search-loading status message hidden">Loading search index…&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="search-input hidden">
&lt;form id="search-form" class="search-form" action="#" method="post" accept-charset="UTF-8" role="search">
&lt;label for="query" class="visually-hidden">Search&lt;/label>
&lt;input type="search" id="query" name="query" class="search-text" placeholder="Enter the terms you wish to search for." maxlength="128">
&lt;button type="submit" name="submit" class="form-submit" >Search&lt;/button>
&lt;/form>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="search-results">&lt;/div>
&lt;template>
&lt;article class="search-result list-view">
&lt;header>
&lt;h2 class="title title-submitted">&lt;a href="#">Title here&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="submitted">&lt;time class="created-date">Date here&lt;/time>&lt;/div>
&lt;/header>
&lt;div class="content">Summary here&lt;/div>
&lt;/article>
&lt;/template></description></item></channel></rss>